https://www.linkedin.com/in/jackhong6 https://github.com/jackhong6

jhong@alumni.ubc.ca | 604 379 8772

RESEARCH

UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO | SUMMER STUDENT

May 2017 - August 2017 | Toronto, ON

Worked with **Professor Jo Bovy** to develop a Python class to represent the gravitational potential of the spiral arms of galaxies in the galpy open source Python library. Used this potential class to investigate the effects of spiral arms on the Oort constants.

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF NANOTECHNOLOGY | SUMMER STUDENT

May 2016 - August 2016 | Edmonton, AB

Worked with **Professor Marek Malak** to develop and test a micro-controller based on the Intel Galileo Gen 2 Development Board (Arduino) for the Hitachi 3D Tomography Holder used in electron microscopes. Programmed the controller in the Arduino language and MATLAB to work with the existing microscopy software (Maestro).

WORK EXPERIENCE

UBC | Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Sep 2014 - Present | Vancouver, BC

- PHYS 109: Enriched Experimental Physics help students in labs, mark lab books (Jan Apr 2016 and Jan Apr 2017)
- PHYS 100: Introductory Physics led a tutorial section, marked exams (Sep 2017 Dec 2017)
- CPSC 101: Computational Thinking led two lab sections, marked projects and exams (Sep 2014 Dec 2014)

CITY OF RICHMOND | LIFEGUARD & SWIMMING INSTRUCTOR

May 2013 - Present | Richmond, BC

- Supervise the pool, treat first aids, respond to patron concerns, perform water tests, and clean the change rooms
- Teach the Red Cross Swim Programs, including preschool, kids, teens, and adults.

IBM | Software Test Engineer

Jan 2016 - April 2016 | Victoria, BC

- Wrote and maintained JUnit 4 and Selenium Webdriver 2.0 tests for IBM Forms Experience Builder software.
- Submitted detailed bug reports that accurately and concisely described the problems found.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF BRITISH COLUMBIA | BSc in Physics

Major in Physics, minor in astronomy | 81% average | Year 4 | Expected graduation May 2019 | Vancouver, BC

LANGUAGES

PROGRAMMING

Python • MATLAB • Java • Shell Script • LATEX •

SPOKEN & WRITTEN

Fluency: English, French Spoken only: Mandarin Chinese